The loser's pretty obvious. They get pushed around, they curl up, hide in a corner. A lot of the time, when there's initial contact, if one of them is too much on the defensive side,
El perdedor es bastante obvio. Es mandoneado, se encoge, se esconde en el rincón. Muchas veces, cuando hay contacto inicial, si uno de ellos está demasiado a la defensiva,
the second one will sort of poke at it, grab at its tentacle and see, "Hey, do you want to fight me, do you want to turn around? Do you want to start a wrestling match?" So it'll just poke and run away. Come back, poke and run away. (Bell ringing) Rule 2: Avoid eye contact. When the octopuses come towards each other to begin the fight, they don't actually face each other. They approach sideways. The defensive octopus tries to face away from the attacker until it's the critical moment it knows there's no way to avoid a fight. GG: Really, the one who's waiting to the last moment is the defensive octopus. (Bell ringing) Rule 3: Flash your colors. The aggressor in a fight will quickly and sharply flash bright black on his arms when he's about to initiate a fight. (Bell ringing) GG: Ooh, and already -- IC: We're seeing some action. Looks like they've spotted each other. GG: Right. So now he's going to come -- He's approaching, but not directly at him. IC: Yeah, they're like almost completely antiparallel. GG: And then right there -- IC: Yeah. They contact, and then their arms clash together. (String music) GG: So we've taken the first steps in understanding fighting in the octopus. And you might be asking yourself: Why does this even matter? Well, these types of curiosity-based research questions can often lead to some unexpected insights and discoveries. We've learned a lot about ourselves from studying marine animals. Squid have taught us about how our neurons communicate, and the horseshoe crab has taught us about how our eyes work. So it's not too far of a stretch to say that some of these behaviors that we're seeing in the California two-spot octopus are similar to ours.
el segundo lo clavará, intentar agarrar su tentáculo y ver, "Oye, ¿quieres pelear conmigo? ¿Quieres darte vuelta? ¿Quieres luchar cuerpo a cuerpo?" Entonces, lo clava y se va. Vuelve, lo clava y se va. (Suena campana de boxeo) [Regla 2: Evita el contacto visual] Cuando los pulpos se acercan para empezar a pelear, no se miran cara a cara. Se acercan de costado. El pulpo a la defensiva intenta no mirar al agresor hasta el punto crucial cuando sabe que es imposible evitar una pelea. GG: ¿Sí? ¿El que espera hasta el último minuto está a la defensiva? IC: Sí. (Suena campana de boxeo) [Regla 3: Muestra tus colores] El agresor en una pelea mostrará rápido y claramente un negro vívido en los brazos cuando está a punto de iniciar la pelea. (Suena campana de boxeo) GG: Oh, ya vemos... IC: Estamos viendo acción. Parece que se han visto. GG: Sí. Ahora va a venir... se le está acercando, pero no directamente. IC: Sí, están casi completamente... anti paralelos. GG: Y luego... ahora. IC: Sí, hacen contacto y luego sus brazos colisionan. (Música de cuerdas) GG: Hemos tomado los primeros pasos para entender el combate del pulpo. Quizás te estés preguntando, "Pero ¿por qué importa esto?" Bueno, estos tipos de preguntas de investigación basadas en la curiosidad muchas veces conducen a ideas y descubrimientos inesperados. Hemos aprendido mucho de nosotros mismos estudiando los animales marinos. El calamar nos enseñó sobre cómo se comunican nuestras neuronas; el cangrejo herradura, sobre cómo funcionan nuestros ojos. Entonces no es una exageración decir que algunos de los comportamientos que vemos en los pulpos de dos manchas de California son similares a los nuestros.